

## Research\_

My research vision is to create smart environments through smart everyday materials (e.g., textile and wood) that can be easily and seamlessly integrated into everyday objects (e.g., garments and furniture) at large scale using established methods (e.g. cutting and assembly). My PhD research focuses on the interaction side, i.e., how humans will interact with smart materials and how to build interfaces of smart materials to support the necessary interactions. My research work involves the design, development, and evaluation of interactions and new interfaces of smart materials. In addition, I am also interested in other topics in Human-Computer Interaction (HCI), such as Wearable Input System, AR/VR interactions, Accessible Interface, and Educational Tool. I have a strong record of 18/20 papers published at top HCI venues (CHI, and UIST) in these topics

### Education

**Dartmouth College**Hanover, NH, USA

PhD of Science - Computer Science Sept. 2018 - Now

XDiscovery lab. Advisor: Xing-Dong Yang

National Taiwan University

Taipei, Taiwan

Master of Science - Computer Science and Engineering Sept. 2015 - Sept. 2017

Mobile & HCI lab. Advisor: Mike Y. Chen

#### **National Taipei University of Technology**

Bachelor of Science - Computer Science and Engineering Sept. 2011 - Sept. 2015

Taipei, Taiwan

Best undergraduate research project award.

### Publications 1 \_\_\_\_\_

#### [C20] iWood: Makeable Vibration Sensor for Interactive Plywood.

Proceedings of the 35th Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology. (UIST'22)

Te-Yen Wu, Xing-Dong Yang

# [C19] NFCStack: Identifiable Physical Building Blocks that Support Concurrent Construction and Frictionless Interaction.

Proceedings of the 35th Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology. (UIST'22)

**Te-Yen Wu**, Huizhong Ye, Chi-Jung Lee, Xing-Dong Yang, Bing-Yu Chen, Rong-Hao Liang

#### [C18] Body-Centric NFC: Body-Centric Interaction with NFC Devices Through Near-Field Enabled Clothing.

In Designing Interactive Systems Conference 2022(DIS'22)

 $\textit{Chi-Jung Lee, Chi-Huan Chiang, Ling-Chien Yang, \textbf{\textit{Te-Yen Wu}}, Rong-Hao\,Liang, Bing-Yu\,Chen}$ 

#### [C17] AccessibleCircuits: Adaptive Add-On Circuit Components for People with Blindness or Low Vision.

Proceedings of the 39th annual ACM conference on human factors in computing systems. (CHI'21)

Ruei-Che Chang, Wen-Ping Wang, Chi-Huan Chiang, Te-Yen Wu, Zheer Xu, Justin Luo, Bing-Yu Chen, Xing-Dong Yang

#### [C16] Project Tasca: Enabling Touch and Contextual Interactions with a Pocket-based Textile Sensor.

Proceedings of the 39th annual ACM conference on human factors in computing systems. (CHI'21)

**Te-Yen Wu**, Zheer Xu, Xing-Dong Yang, Steve Hodge ,Teddy Seyed

#### [C15] Capacitivo: Contact-Based Object Recognition on Interactive Fabrics using Capacitive Sensing.

 $Proceedings \ of the \ 33th \ Annual \ ACM \ Symposium \ on \ User \ Interface \ Software \ and \ Technology. \ \textbf{(UIST'20)}$ 

**Te-Yen Wu**, Lu Tan, Yuji Zhang, Teddy Seyed, Xing-Dong Yang

#### [C14] Fabriccio: Touchless Gestural Input on Interactive Fabrics.

Proceedings of the 38th annual ACM conference on human factors in computing systems. (CHI'20)

**Te-Yen Wu**, Shutong Qi, Junchi Chen, MuJie Shang, Jun Gong, Teddy Seyed, Xing-Dong Yang

<sup>&</sup>lt;sup>1</sup>In the field of Human-Computer Interaction, the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI) and ACM Symposium on User Interface Software Technology (UIST) are considered top tier forums for timely and impactful work, which have an annual acceptance rate of around 20 - 25%.

#### [C13] TangibleCircuits: An Interactive 3D Printed Circuit Education Tool for People with Visual Impairments.

Proceedings of the 38th annual ACM conference on human factors in computing systems. (CHI'20 Honorable Mention Award)

Josh Urban Davis, **Te-Yen Wu**, Bo Shi, Hanyi Lu, Athina Panotopoulou, Emily Whiting, Xing-Dong Yang

#### [C12] Zippro: The Design and Implementation of An Interactive Zipper.

Proceedings of the 38th annual ACM conference on human factors in computing systems. (CHI'20)

Pin-Sung Ku, Jun Gong, **Te-Yen Wu**, Yixin Wei, Yiwen Tang, Barrett Ens, Xing-Dong Yang

#### [C11] ThreadSense: Locating Touch on an Extremely Thin Interactive Thread.

Proceedings of the 38th annual ACM conference on human factors in computing systems. (CHI'20)

Pin-Sung Ku, Qijia Shao, **Te-Yen Wu**, Jun Gong, Ziyan Zhu, Xia Zhou, Xing-Dong Yang

#### [C10] BiTipText: Bimanual Eyes-Free Text Entry on a Fingertip Keyboard

Proceedings of the 38th annual ACM conference on human factors in computing systems. (CHI'20)

Zheer Xu, Weihao Chen, Dongyang Zhao, Jiehui Luo, Te-Yen Wu, Jun Gong, Sicheng Yin, Jialun Zhai, Xing-Dong Yang

#### [C9] Proxino: Enabling Prototyping of Virtual Circuits With Physical Proxies.

Proceedings of the 32th Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology. (UIST'19)

Te-Yen Wu, Jun Gong, Teddy Seyed, Xing-Dong Yang

#### [C8] TipText, Eyes-Free Text Entry on a Fingertip Keyboard.

Proceedings of the 32th Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology. (UIST'19 Best Paper Award)

Zheer Xu, Pui Chung Wong, Jun Gong, Te-Yen Wu, Aditya Shekhar Nittala, Xiaojun Bi, Jürgen Steimle, Hongbo Fu, Kening Zhu, Xing-Dong Yang

# [C7] ARPilot: 6DOF Direct-Manipulation Interface for Drone Videography using Augmented Reality on Mobile Devices.

Proceedings of the 20th International Conference on Human-Computer Interaction with Mobile Devices and Services (MobileHCl'18)

Yu-An Chen, Te-Yen Wu, Tim Chang, Jun You Liu, Yuan-Chang Shieh, Leon Yulun Hsu, Ming-Wei Hsu, Paul Taele, Neng-Hao Yu, Mike Y. Chen

#### [C6] ActiveErgo: Automatic and Personalized Ergonomics using Self-actuating Furniture

Proceedings of the 36th annual ACM conference on human factors in computing systems (CHI '18)

Yu-Chian Wu, **Te-Yen Wu**, Yu-Chih Lin, Pin-sung Ku, Paul Taele, Po-En Lai, Bryan Wang, Mike Y. Chen

# [C5] SpeechBubbles: Enhancing the Captioning Experience for Users with Hearing-impairment in Group Conversations.

Proceedings of the 36th annual ACM conference on human factors in computing systems (CHI '18)

Ming-Mei Hsu, Yi-Hao Peng, Ting-Tu Lin, Leon Hsu, Po-En Lai, Paul Taele, Te-Yen Wu, Hsien-Hui Tang, Mike Y. Chen

# [C4] CircuitSense: Automatic Sensing of Physical Circuits and Generation of Virtual Circuits to Support Software Tools.

Proceedings of the 32th Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology. (UIST'17)

**Te-Yen Wu**, Bryan Wang, Jiun-Yu Lee, Hao-Ping Shen, Yu-Chian Wu, Yu-An Chen, Pin-Sung Ku, Ming-Wei Hsu, Yu-Chih Lin, Mike Y. Chen

#### [C3] CurrentViz: Sensing and Visualizing Electric Current of Breadboarded Circuits.

Proceedings of the 30th Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology. (UIST'17)

Te-Yen Wu, Hao-Ping Shen, Yu-Chian Wu, Yu-An Chen, Pin-Sung Ku, Ming-Wei Hsu, Jun-You Liu, Yu-Chih Lin, Mike Y. Chen.

#### [C2] CircuitStack: Supporting Rapid Prototyping and Evolution of Electronic Circuits.

Proceedings of the 29th Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology. (UIST'16)

Chiuan Wang, Hsuan-Ming Yeh, Bryan Wang, Te-Yen Wu, Hsin-Ruey Tsai, Rong-Hao Liang, Yi-Ping Hung, Mike Y. Chen.

# [C1] Giggler: An Intuitive, Real-Time Integrated Wireless In-Ear Monitoring and Personal Mixing System using Mobile Devices.

Proceedings of the 23rd ACM international conference on Multimedia (MM'15)

Andries Valstar, Min-Chieh Hsiu, **Te-Yen Wu**, Mike Y. Chen

### Posters & Demos

[VRST 2017 Poster] EyeExpression: Exploring The Use of Eye Expressions As Hands-free Input for Virtual and Augmented reality devices Pin-Sung Ku, Te-Yen Wu, and Mike Y. Chen.

#### [VRST 2017 Poster] PeriText+: Utilizing Peripheral Vision for Reading Text on Augmented Reality Smart Glasses

Yu-Chih Lin, Jun-You Liu, Yu-Chian Wu, Pin-Sung Ku, Katherine Chen, **Te-Yen Wu**, Yu-An Chen, and Mike Y. Chen.

### [UIST 2017 Demo] CurrentViz: Sensing and Visualizing Electric Current of Breadboarded Circuits Te-Yen Wu, Hao-Ping

Shen, Yu-Chian Wu, Yu-An Chen, Pin-Sung Ku, Ming-Wei Hsu, Jun-You Liu, Yu-Chih Lin, and Mike Y. Chen.

#### [CHI 2017 Poster] SegTouch: Enhancing Touch Input While Providing Touch Gestures on Screens Using

**Thumb-To-Index-Finger Gestures** Hsin-Ruey Tsai, **Te-Yen Wu**, Da-Yuan Huang, Min-Chieh Hsiu, Jui-Chun Hsiao, Yi-Ping Hung, Mike Y. Chen, and Bing-Yu Chen

[CHI 2017 Student Game Competition] Party Animals: Creating Immersive Gaming Experience for Physically Co-present VR and Non-VR Players Ming-Wei Hsu, Te-Yen Wu, Yu-Chian Wu, Yu-An Chen, Yu-Chih Lin, and Pin-Sung Ku.

[UIST 2016 Demo] CircuitStack: Supporting Rapid Prototyping and Evolution of Electronic Circuits Chiuan Wang, Hsuan-Ming Yeh, Bryan Wang, Te-Yen Wu, Hsin-Ruey Tsai, Rong-Hao Liang, Yi-Ping Hung, and Mike Y. Chen.

### Selected Patents

[P3] Peer-to-Peer Communication via Smart Wearables (Microsoft)

[P2] A Smart Fabric Technique That Recognizes Metallic and Non-Metallic Objects, as well as Touch Input (Dartmouth)

[P1] Enabling Prototyping of Virtual Circuits With Physical Proxies. (Dartmouth)

## **Selected Press Coverage** \_\_\_\_\_

**Engadget** Smart fabric can recognize the food you put on the table

**TechExplore** Capacitivo: A contact-sensitive technique that can be used to make smart tablecloths

The Science Times Smart Fabric Can Suggest What Meal To Cook Based on What's On the Table

**Telegraph UK** Microsoft's smart tablecloth tells you what to dish up for dinner

**Ethical Editor** Capacitivo: A contact-sensitive technique that can be used to make smart tablecloths

**Drew Reports News** Smart Fabric Can Recognize the Food You Keep on Your Table

**SomagNews** The smart fabric can recognize the objects you put in!

# **Work Experience**

Lead a new wearable input system for Metaverse with filing one patent

**Research Intern, Microsoft Research** 

Contribute a new wearable system and infrastructure for smart garments

Research Intern, Microsoft Research

 $Invent\ a\ new\ smart\ pocket\ for\ enabling\ touch\ and\ contextual\ interactions,\ with\ one\ paper\ published$ 

**Research Assistant, National Taiwan University** 

Lead lab research projects and mentor Grad/UnderGrad Students, with three papers published

Android App Intern, Yahoo

Develop and Ship chatbot and chromecast features in Yahoo Android App.

**Android Instructor, Information System Training Program** 

Teach Android basic framework and lead students to build a drinking order app.

Fullstack Software Engineer, Bearsoft Inc.

Develop and ship chatbot features in IOS App.

Founder, HydraBrain Game Studio

Develop and publish an innovative 2D game on Windows Store and Google Play

Redmond, Seattle

June. 2022 - Sept. 2022

Redmond, Seattle

June. 2021 - Sept. 2021

Redmond, Seattle
June. 2020 - Sept. 2020

Taipei, Taiwan

Sept. 2017 - June. 2018

Taipei, Taiwan

July. 2017 - Aug. 2017

Taipei, Taiwan

Mar. 2016 - Sept. 2016

Taipei, Taiwan Feb. 2015 - Jun. 2015

Taipei, Taiwan

Feb. 2014 - Jun. 2015

## Skills

**Programming Languages** C/C++, C#, Python, JAVA, Node JS, Objective-C, and Swift **Software Platforms and Tools** Android, IOS, QT, Unity, OpenCV, Sklearn, and TensorFlow

**Firmware and Hardware** Arduino, Keil, RF Circuit Design, PCB Design

**Domain Knowledge** Digital Signal Processing, Machine Learning, IoT Infrastructure, and Human-Computer Interaction

# **Academic Services** \_\_\_\_

CHI 2021 Program Committee Associate Chair (AC), Late Breaking Work

 ${\it CHI~2020~ \textbf{Program Committee Associate Chair (AC)},~ Late~ Breaking~ Work}$ 

 $\textbf{Special Recognition for Outstanding Reviews}, \ \mathsf{UIST}\ 2021$ 

Reviewer (44 reviews), CHI, UIST, IMWUT, MobileHCI, TEI, CSCW, ISS